<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ibnulab</title><link>https://ibnulab.pages.dev/</link><description>Recent content on Ibnulab</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ibnulab.pages.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Welcome to my world!</title><link>https://ibnulab.pages.dev/p/welcome-to-my-world/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ibnulab.pages.dev/p/welcome-to-my-world/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="welcome">Welcome
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Phew, first off, I&amp;rsquo;d like to say that making a website isn&amp;rsquo;t as easy as I thought. But it was worth the effort!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Welcome to my page! This website will mostly be used to write my own blog, my projects that I&amp;rsquo;ve done, or just to store my ideas and stories. Even though I&amp;rsquo;m not particularly someone who notes a lot, I hope this will give me the motivation.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="notes-about-my-experience-making-website-with-hugo">Notes about my experience making website with Hugo
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>Wow the journey was kinda long and far. I&amp;rsquo;m finally able to deploy this static website on cloudflare pages. I&amp;rsquo;m really new to all these, and even with proper guide and template, I was lost quite a lot.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With that said, I&amp;rsquo;m proud to have reached this far.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="nasi-uduk">Nasi Uduk
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>Yes, it&amp;rsquo;s best food for breakfast, ever, period.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Archives</title><link>https://ibnulab.pages.dev/archives/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ibnulab.pages.dev/archives/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Customer Growth through Profiling</title><link>https://ibnulab.pages.dev/p/customer-growth-through-profiling/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ibnulab.pages.dev/p/customer-growth-through-profiling/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://ibnulab.pages.dev/p/customer-growth-through-profiling/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Customer Growth through Profiling" />&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>In 2023, TheLook Ecommerce experienced remarkable growth in gross merchandise value (GMV), reaching nearly $3 million, a fivefold increase from the previous year. This success was reflected in the exponential rise in the number of transactions and customer base expansion. However, this growth masked a concerning trend—customer acquisition was slowing down. By the end of 2023, the company saw a 24.43% decline in customer acquisition, with the second half of the year showing a sharp drop of up to 50%. This alarming trend posed a significant challenge: how to sustain business growth when the influx of new customers was dwindling.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Read the summary below or visit the full report &lt;a class="link" href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1G_4Q6J5wm3tIFckUGJes5LKb_MupIr_t71eNmy4eQmM/edit?usp=sharing" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>here&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="segmenting-the-customer-base">Segmenting the Customer Base
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>To address this challenge, the analysis focused on understanding customer profile and behavior through segmentation. Four distinct customer groups were identified:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>VVIP:&lt;/strong> This group, representing only 5% of the customer base, contributed a significant 23% of the total GMV. These top spenders are the most valuable customers.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Premier:&lt;/strong> Comprising 22% of customers, this group had better spending power than average customers and accounted for 38% of the GMV.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Majority:&lt;/strong> The largest segment, making up 49% of the customer base, contributed 25% of the GMV. This group had high transaction volumes but lower average revenue per user (ARPU).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Churned:&lt;/strong> These customers, who had not made a purchase in over a year, represented 22% of the customer base and contributed 12% of the GMV.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The segmentation was achieved through clustering analysis, considering metrics such as GMV, ARPU, transaction history, and other behavioral data. The goal was to identify patterns within these groups to tailor strategies that could boost customer retention and acquisition.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="key-findings-and-behavioral-insights">Key Findings and Behavioral Insights
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>The analysis revealed significant behavioral shifts in 2023. The &amp;ldquo;Majority&amp;rdquo; group saw a spike in activity and GMV, while the &amp;ldquo;Churned&amp;rdquo; group continued to decline. It was hypothesized that a business change in late 2022 or early 2023 might have contributed to these shifts—attracting more activity from the &amp;ldquo;Majority&amp;rdquo; while losing interest from the &amp;ldquo;Churned.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The impact analysis showed that focusing on specific customer groups could lead to measurable improvements in GMV. Targeting the VVIP and Premier segments was projected to increase GMV by 3.11%, while efforts to engage the Majority and Churned groups could yield additional increases of 1.27% and 0.63%, respectively.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="strategic-focus-areas">Strategic Focus Areas
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Given these findings, the analysis recommends a multi-faceted approach to drive growth:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Prioritize Top Customers:&lt;/strong> Focus on the VVIP and Premier groups to secure a substantial portion of GMV with relatively low effort. These customers are already high spenders, and nurturing their loyalty could yield significant returns.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Engage the Majority:&lt;/strong> While they contribute less per transaction, the Majority group is large and active. Maintaining their engagement and encouraging incremental spending could provide steady growth.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Reactivate Churned Customers:&lt;/strong> Though they currently represent a smaller portion of GMV, re-engaging Churned customers could be worthwhile. Even a small percentage of reactivation could lead to a meaningful increase in revenue.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>In conclusion, while TheLook Ecommerce has enjoyed substantial growth, the slowing rate of customer acquisition requires immediate attention. By understanding and segmenting the customer base, the company can implement targeted strategies that not only retain high-value customers but also re-engage those who have lapsed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Passenger Satisfaction Analysis</title><link>https://ibnulab.pages.dev/p/passenger-satisfaction-analysis/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ibnulab.pages.dev/p/passenger-satisfaction-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://ibnulab.pages.dev/p/passenger-satisfaction-analysis/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Passenger Satisfaction Analysis" />&lt;h2 id="summary">Summary
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Revo Air passenger satisfaction is declining, and in order to engage more customers, we must improve our service quality. So, we launched a survey to our passengers about their experience flying with us. After the analysis, we found 3 services as our main priority to improve on, namely: Online Boarding, Inflight Entertainment, and Seat Comfort.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="current-situation">Current Situation
&lt;/h2>&lt;div style="display: block;">
&lt;img src="current-situation.webp" alt="current situation of the business" style="width: 60%; height: auto; float: right; margin-left: 20px; margin-bottom: 20px;"/>
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;">
From the survey results, we find out that Revo Air only receives 43% satisfaction level which is pretty concerning for our business. So we have to improve the service to increase satisfaction level to 60% in 2023.&lt;br>&lt;br>
We managed to identify the characteristics of the dissatisfied passengers. They are within the age of 8-38 and 60+ group. They were in the Eco and Eco Plus Class. They were on a personal travel. Both our Member and Non-Member passengers. And that they were on a short-haul flight (Under 1000 Miles). The last part is the one that surprised us. Our initial hypothesis was that the longer the distance the more dissatisfied the passenger will be. The truth is passengers that traveled more than 1500 miles are satisfied with their flight, while passengers that traveled under 1000 miles (short-distance flight) are mostly dissatisfied.
&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="result">Result
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>We analyze the data using 3 methods: EDA, Correlation and Clustering Analysis&lt;/p>
&lt;div>
&lt;img src="average-score.webp" alt="Average Score" style="width: 100%; height: auto; display: block; margin-bottom: 10px;"/>
&lt;img src="correlation-score.webp" alt="Correlation Score" style="width: 100%; height: auto; display: block; margin-bottom: 10px;"/>
&lt;img src="clustering-result.webp" alt="Clustering Result" style="width: 100%; height: auto; display: block; margin-bottom: 10px;"/>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>From the result shown above, we concluded 2 things:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>We need to focus on 3 services, namely: Online Boarding, Inflight Entertainment, and Seat Comfort.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>We need to focus on the 2nd cluster, which is where the majority of dissatisfied passengers are identified in.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>As for our recommendation, you can read more details on our &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.canva.com/design/DAFBZzawX7Y/q30BuRiVnDIE-Xi0Iu4_cQ/view?utm_content=DAFBZzawX7Y&amp;amp;utm_campaign=designshare&amp;amp;utm_medium=link&amp;amp;utm_source=publishsharelink" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>&lt;strong>Canva Presentation&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>About me</title><link>https://ibnulab.pages.dev/about-me/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ibnulab.pages.dev/about-me/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hi, my name is Ibnu. I’m currently enjoying life by learning and implementing my skill as a Data Analyst. I’m always looking for ways to improve myself and help others.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have over 2 years of experience turning numbers into meaningful stories that help businesses grow. I enjoy building dashboards, creating ETL pipelines, and simplifying complex data into insights that people can act on. I’ve also mentored aspiring analysts by designing hands-on learning programs, boosting learning outcomes by 10% with data-driven tweaks. Lately, I’ve been diving into e-commerce and marketing analytics, sharpening my skills in spotting trends and solving business problems. Whether it’s automating reports to save time or uncovering patterns in the data, I’m all about using data to make smarter decisions and drive results.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="past-experience">Past Experience
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Short summary, while it&amp;rsquo;s not my official title, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working as a data analyst for about 2 years. I was a career switcher, while it was a risky and tough choice, it was one the proudest decision I&amp;rsquo;ve made in my professional life.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="curriculum-team-for-data-analytics-program-at-revou">Curriculum Team for Data Analytics Program at RevoU
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>This is an interesting experience for me. As I was still learning about data analytics itself, I was also helping others learn data analytics. I get to see different way of people’s behavior in learning, and being able to support them in their job seeking journey has been fulfilling.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Notable Achievements:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Built dashboards to monitor 500+ students’ performance, identifying trends that improved student performance by 15%.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Designed and updated curriculum to meet market demands, focusing on essential data manipulation, data analysis, basic statistics, and practical skills required for entry-level data analysts.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Streamlined and automated ETL pipelines using Python and Appscript, reducing data integration time by 30% and enabling quick student performance tracking.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Partnered with external clients to better support students’ job search efforts, including analyzing industry-specific projects and enhancing communication skills for data analysts.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Provided guidance to students, ensuring they understood project objectives and gained relevant business knowledge, aligning their learning with real-world applications.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Search</title><link>https://ibnulab.pages.dev/search/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ibnulab.pages.dev/search/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>