<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pages on Ibnulab</title><link>https://ibnulab.pages.dev/page/</link><description>Recent content in Pages on Ibnulab</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ibnulab.pages.dev/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Archives</title><link>https://ibnulab.pages.dev/archives/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ibnulab.pages.dev/archives/</guid><description/></item><item><title>About me</title><link>https://ibnulab.pages.dev/about-me/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ibnulab.pages.dev/about-me/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hi, my name is Ibnu. I’m currently enjoying life by learning and implementing my skill as a Data Analyst. I’m always looking for ways to improve myself and help others.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have over 2 years of experience turning numbers into meaningful stories that help businesses grow. I enjoy building dashboards, creating ETL pipelines, and simplifying complex data into insights that people can act on. I’ve also mentored aspiring analysts by designing hands-on learning programs, boosting learning outcomes by 10% with data-driven tweaks. Lately, I’ve been diving into e-commerce and marketing analytics, sharpening my skills in spotting trends and solving business problems. Whether it’s automating reports to save time or uncovering patterns in the data, I’m all about using data to make smarter decisions and drive results.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="past-experience">Past Experience
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Short summary, while it&amp;rsquo;s not my official title, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working as a data analyst for about 2 years. I was a career switcher, while it was a risky and tough choice, it was one the proudest decision I&amp;rsquo;ve made in my professional life.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="curriculum-team-for-data-analytics-program-at-revou">Curriculum Team for Data Analytics Program at RevoU
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>This is an interesting experience for me. As I was still learning about data analytics itself, I was also helping others learn data analytics. I get to see different way of people’s behavior in learning, and being able to support them in their job seeking journey has been fulfilling.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Notable Achievements:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Built dashboards to monitor 500+ students’ performance, identifying trends that improved student performance by 15%.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Designed and updated curriculum to meet market demands, focusing on essential data manipulation, data analysis, basic statistics, and practical skills required for entry-level data analysts.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Streamlined and automated ETL pipelines using Python and Appscript, reducing data integration time by 30% and enabling quick student performance tracking.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Partnered with external clients to better support students’ job search efforts, including analyzing industry-specific projects and enhancing communication skills for data analysts.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Provided guidance to students, ensuring they understood project objectives and gained relevant business knowledge, aligning their learning with real-world applications.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Search</title><link>https://ibnulab.pages.dev/search/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ibnulab.pages.dev/search/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>